SURENDRAN GOPINATHAN





www.linkedin.com/in/surendran-gopinathan



79 Elmwood downs, Magheranan, Letterkenny

+353 899434636

surendran17.02@gmail.com

SUMMARY

PROFESSIONAL Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 4 years of experience working in a SCRUM environment as part of Integration team in Pharmaceutical sector. Thrives within tight deadlines by applying agile development strategies.

Self Learner and Highly Adaptable to change and new platforms.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

May 2019 - Aug 2022

Accenture

- Designing and developing solutions as part of middleware/Integration Team.
- Creating Workflows using Camunda Modeler to automate the existing solutions.
- Creating Database objects (Oracle PL/SQL) to handle complex business logic.
- Developing backend rest API's for web application.
- Managing Sprints in gitlab/Jira by creating and tracking issues with proper labels and milestones.
- Experienced in all phases of SDLC including analysis, design, coding and testing.
- Addressing business Critical issues that were affecting Customers and quickly solving
- Serve as primary contact for the client and maintain healthy relationship to guarantee continuous business growth.
- Actively listened to client objectives and concerns and ensured top quality deliverables
- Good understanding about Jenkins and Gitlab CI/CD Pipelines.

Associate Software Engineer Aug 2018 - Apr 2019

Accenture

- Consult with users, management, and technical personnel to clarify business issues, identify problems and suggest changes/solutions
- Support incident management and problem management.
- Creating interfaces using java and pl/sql to transfer/receive files.
- Manage and coordinate hot fix and maintenance releases.
- Provide support to the business during day-to-day activities and ad-hoc requests during on-call.
- Assist with troubleshooting and issue resolution relating to current applications, providing assistance to the development
- Providing knowledge transfer to new resources.

SKILLS

- Java
- Oracle PL/SQL
- Camunda Workflow
- Python
- Restful API
- Git
- Maven
- Gitlab CI/CD
- Basic Unix/Bash

INTERESTS

- Table Tennis
- Football
- Esports
- Competitive Programming

EDUCATION

Meenakshi Sundararajan Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering

2014 - 2018

8.01 GPA